Guilherme Nunes Trofino

[EN version]

guitrofino@gmail.com LinkedIn: guilherme-trofino GitHub: tr0fin0 +33 07 49 18 55 00

Summary

I'm Guilherme, a 23-year-old Brazilian student from UNICAMP, pursu- I'm looking for a 5-month internship from the 25th of March until ing since 2022 a 3-year double degree exchange program at ENSTA Paris the 9th of September in Robotics, Electronics, or PCB design. master's program.

Experience

Retail Vendor Manager Intern

Amazon France

Clichy, France

09/2023 - 03/2024

In collaboration with a Senior Vendor Manager, I helped provide tools designed to optimize business performance and drive sales growth. This included an Excel macro designed to identify licensed selection twenth times faster, allowing deep dives in large datasets, uncovering trends, extracting customer insights, and taking action.

I also developed a comprehensive and visually appealing Dashboard in Excel, facilitating benchmarking at various levels of granularity, simplifying the identification of growth opportunities and the implementation of new strategies for the team.

Neuroscience Research Intern

ISIR. Sorbonne Université

Paris, France

05/2023 - 08/2023

Developing a user-friendly simulation environment using Webots and Python, facilitating the assessment of the sensorimotor modelization of the hippocampus based on the framework proposed by Benoît Girard and Sylvain Argentieri.

Head of Team

Phoenix Robotics Team of UNICAMP

Campinas, Brazil 07/2021 - 07/2022

Established in 2001 by mechatronics engineering students, the Phoenix Robotic Team had, in 2022, 83 undergraduate students from different courses designing, building, and competing with autonomous and radio-controlled robots across 12 categories.

Definition of long-term planning for the Team's departments and projects aiming for sustainable growth, resulting in a new people-driven culture and mission setting short and medium-term targets and deadlines for the 5 area coordinators and the 12 project coordinators.

Improve Team Members' selection process, aiming for more diversity, resulting in the best inscription ratio, over 125 people from 500, and resulting in the best percentage of women among the approved, 16 from 35 people.

Head of Electronics Department

Phoenix Robotics Team of UNICAMP

Campinas, Brazil

08/2020 - 07/2021

During this timeframe, we closed a strategic partnership with Altium, securing access to Altium Designer and Altium 365, and we implemented a 10-week project-based training program, onboarding 12 people to the team.

Education

MSc Engineering | Double degree

ENSTA Paris, IP Paris Computer Science - Robotics

Palaiseau, France

07/2022 - Present

BSc Engineering | Double degree

FEM, UNICAMP

Campinas, Brazil

03/2019 - Present

Control and Automation - Mechatronics

Languages

Skills

Portuguese: Native French: Advanced C1 Programming: C, LaTeX, MATLAB, Python and VBA

Office: Excel, PowerPoint and Word

English: Advanced C1 Others: Altium Designer, Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop

Guilherme Nunes Trofino

[FR version] GitHub: tr0fin0

guitrofino@gmail.com

LinkedIn: guilherme-trofino

+33 07 49 18 55 00

Résumé

Je m'appelle Guilherme, un étudiant brésilien de 23 ans de l'UNICAMP, Je recherche une stage de césure de 5 mois entre le 25 mars jusqu'à poursuivant depuis 2022 un double diplôme de 3 ans à l'ENSTA Paris au le 9 septembre en Robotics, Electronics, or PCB design. programme de master.

Expérience

Retail Vendor Manager Intern

Amazon France

Clichy, France 09/2023 - 03/2024

En collaboration avec un Senior Vendor Manager, j'ai aidé à fournir des outils conçus pour optimiser les performances commerciales et stimuler la croissance des ventes. Cela incluait un macro Excel conçu pour identifier la sélection sous licence vingt fois plus vite, permettant des analyses approfondies dans de grands ensembles de données, découvrant des tendances et extrayant des insights clients.

J'ai également développé un dashboard complet et visuellement attrayant dans Excel, facilitant le benchmarking à différents niveaux de granularité, simplifiant l'identification des opportunités de croissance et la mise en œuvre de nouvelles stratégies pour l'équipe.

Neuroscience Research Intern

ISIR, Sorbonne Université

Paris, France

05/2023 - 08/2023

Développement d'un environnement de simulation utilisant Webots et Python, facilitant l'évaluation de la modélisation sensorimotrice de l'hippocampe basée sur le cadre proposé par Benoît Girard et Sylvain Argentieri.

Head of Team

Phoenix Robotics Team of UNICAMP

Campinas, Brazil 07/2021 - 07/2022

Fondée en 2001 par des étudiants en génie mécatronique, l'équipe Phoenix Robotic comptait, en 2022, 83 étudiants de premier cycle issus de différentes filières concevant, construisant et concourant avec des robots autonomes et radiocommandés dans 12 catégories différentes.

Définition d'une planification à long terme pour les départements et projets de l'équipe visant une croissance durable, ce qui a conduit à une nouvelle culture axée sur les personnes et à la définition d'objectifs à court et moyen terme ainsi que de délais pour les 5 coordinateurs de zone et les 12 coordinateurs de projet.

Amélioration du processus de sélection des membres de l'équipe, visant une plus grande diversité, ce qui a abouti au meilleur ratio d'inscription, plus de 125 personnes sur 500, et au meilleur pourcentage de femmes parmi les approuvés, 16 sur 35 personnes.

Head of Electronics Department

Phoenix Robotics Team of UNICAMP

Campinas, Brazil

08/2020 - 07/2021

Au cours de cette période, nous avons conclu un partenariat stratégique avec Altium, garantissant l'accès à Altium Designer et à Altium 365, et nous avons mis en place un programme de formation par projet de 10 semaines, intégrant 12 personnes à l'équipe.

Éducation

MSc Ingénierie | Double Diplôme

ENSTA Paris, IP Paris Palaiseau, France 07/2022 - Present

Informatique - Robotique

BSc Ingénierie | Double Diplôme

FEM, UNICAMP Campinas, Brazil 03/2019 - Present

Contrôle et Automatisation – Mécatronique

Skills Langues

Programmation: C, LaTeX, MATLAB, Python and VBA Portugais: Langue Materne

Français: Avancé C1 Office: Excel, PowerPoint and Word

Anglais: Avancé C1 Outres: Altium Designer, Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop